Okay, now the now the recording has
started.
>> Thank you, Johnny. Uh, good morning
everyone. My name is Jorge Gonzalez. I'm
the medical psilocybin program manager.
We're here with staff from the
department of health and we're also here
with Ian Dunn who is the chair of the uh
dosa administration clinical practice
committee and also the chair of the
advisory board. Uh just want you to
remember that this meeting is being
recorded. Please keep uh when it time
comes for public comment please uh keep
your language appropriate. So this is
recorded as I said and will be posted on
our website with that Ian uh you are
ready to go.
>> Perfect. Uh thank you everyone. My name
is Ian Dunn. I am the chair of the
dosage administration and clinical
practice committee. Uh thank you
everyone for to joining today's meeting.
Today's objectives are to begin the
review and development of integration
session guidance. Uh we had some ideas
so I got a rough draft started. Um
definitely still up to input, change,
recommendation. Um as a reminder,
committees operate in an advisory
capacity. They provide a forum for
individuals who may not who may be
experts but may not serve on the board
due to a real or perceived conflict of
interest. reminder that we cannot change
or alter the medical psilocybin act. We
have to work within the law. Um
committees support the board by
expanding community input, incorporating
subject matter expertise, increasing
participation in program development. I
will now turn over if you would like to
participate in today's committee
meeting. Please share your name, your
role or area of expertise, and your
perspective or interest related to
dosage administration and clinical
practice. Thank you.
And if you would like to introduce
yourself, you may now raise your hand at
this time.
Perfect. I see Gregory Evans.
I'm still trying to dose myself with
coffee.
relatable.
Um, [clears throat] yeah, I don't have
much. My name is Gregory Evans.
I independent researcher and micologist.
Uh, yeah, whatever you need, I'm here.
Santa Fe, something like that. It's all
I got.
>> Thank you. All righty. I do not see any
other hands. I do see uh some chats
waiting, so I will go ahead and wait for
them to finish introducing themselves.
>> But Jorge, if you wouldn't mind pulling
up the
uh integration document that I have
started working on.
>> I sure will.
>> And then we have an introduction from
Don Moser, Las Vegas, New Mexico. Um he
says he's glad to be here.
Alrighty. So
the purpose and scope of integration is
the structured structured process of
processing making sense of and weaving
the insights, emotions and experiences
gained during a psilocybin
administration session into a patient's
daily life uh ongoing treatment and
long-term health goals. The purpose of
integration is to support the
translation of acute psychedelic
experiences into meaningful and
sustained psychological behavioral and
functional change while promoting
patient safety and continuity of care.
Um, this document provides clinical best
practices for licensed practitioners and
facilitators participating in New
Mexico's medical psilocybin program. It
is intended to promote consistent
patient- centered and evidenceinformed
integration practices. Um, that's pretty
default and very fun way of saying it's
meant to show how people process their
psilocybin experiences after the
session. So some general pre principles
and if you have any to add please let me
know. Um integration planning should
begin during the preparation phase of
treatment whenever practicable.
Integration appointments should be
scheduled before the administration
session. Um so patients are not expected
to coordinate follow-up care immediately
after treatment. Individualized care
integration should be tailored to the
patients clinical presentation, their
treatment goals, their cultural
background and response to
administration session. Providers should
adjust the timing, frequency, and
intensity of integration sessions when
clinically indicated and including a
following a particularly challenging or
highly meaningful experience. An
integration should always remain
collaborative and non-directive. PA
practitioners should be supporting
patients in exploring the meaning of
their experiences without imposing
personal beliefs, spiritual frameworks,
philosophical interpretations, or
specific inclusions. Um, I do see
Gregory's hand up.
>> Yeah. Can we go back and
get like can you define integration?
>> Do we have as a program? Do we have a
definition? is like literally like if do
we have a dictionary like do we have
like do have we defined the term
>> in the related latest rules we didn't
define what integration is right
>> sorry I I believe so let me let me pull
those up and give me one second while I
pull up the latest version okay give me
a second
>> yeah this is this is a really
[clears throat] important point where we
can just start with a definition before
we decide how to implement the thing.
Let's as a group understand what the
term means
and go around the room.
What does integration mean?
I mean
uh I don't see any hands but if you
would like to share what integration
means please raise your hand
>> or you can also throw it in the chat.
>> Yeah I mean like I'm a micologist.
I
grow mushrooms. There are a lot of
people better suited to define this term
than me.
I don't see a lot of people in today's
meeting. Oh, and we're not going to vote
on anything today. This is kind of the
>> preliminary. I understand that, but it's
just a principle. Like in December, I
sent in a glossery of terms to discuss
and like nobody's interested in like
definitions. Nobody's
[clears throat] early, uncaffeinated,
slightly frustrated.
But let's like be like like this is like
when we're building anything like get
the definition.
>> So I consider integration any post
contact point. Um I even include like
sometime between like the first three
days you um
>> I put that in the chat
>> should check in and say uh you know how
are you feeling like it doesn't have to
be like a deep you know encounter
directly after but it just making sure
hey are you doing okay any hard
experiences like I would consider that a
part of integration maybe not
integration as a whole um but to me and
let's see to the department's point they
say integration session means a
therapeutic encounter occurring between
a certified practitioner and a patient
after the administration of medical
psilocybin in which the practitioner
provides ongoing care to the patient. So
very similar um therapeutic encounter
after medical psilocybin.
So that's an integration Oh sorry am my
mic on yes that's an integration
session. So [clears throat]
zooming out we have preparation we have
a dosage session and then we have
integration
an integration session
I think here
[clears throat] we have guidance in the
rules [gasps and sighs]
that defines that some period of time
after this doest there has to be a thing
with a with the with uh provider.
So the provider has a time where they
meet with the person and they go over
the things that happen during the thing.
That is like a check-in. That is like
your um I had a name for that.
Um [clears throat]
integration is the pro like please like
this is not like
prepared but it's like you have a
definition for integration session still
need a definition for integration
integration being the the whole lifetime
of folding in the meaning of experiences
integration
have you ever had a psychedelic
experience
like have you ever six months later
you're like oh my goodness
like that make now. Oh, okay. And so
like some of the things that lead us to
the path of repatterning our behavior,
the process of patterning, the process
of change, the process of understanding
[snorts] like those are integration.
A therapeutic session is a a one hour
with a person
So they can record the experience, they
can hold the space, they can help you
build a plan. What you have defined here
is somewhere in between
like it's like there's [clears throat] a
treatment plan. An integration plan is a
part of the treatment plan.
[clears throat]
You plan your therapy and you kind of
throw a ball at the things you might do
for integration. Your therapist should
have check-in points
over I don't know this is something we
need to walk through with um research
and continuous improvement because there
are data points that we want to collect
in in research
to follow up with integr integration
over the course of you know 6 months a
year five years. So
if we con constrain the term to mean you
take
hold on one sec.
Yeah. I just don't want to put paint
ourselves into a box because it's not
like the check-in session after the
after the therapy after the dosing
session that like that's not
integration,
>> right? But it is the start of
integration. So
>> integration should start.
>> Integration is a long process. It's the
incorporation
of your mental processes into a normal
effective personality
essentially. So I think that if we think
of it as integration session as um one
time yes it falls far short but if we
consider the fact that after integration
they can reassess and say how much do we
need another check-in maybe quicker cuz
I've met patients that have processed
very very quickly after a psilocybin
experience and I've also had patients
where you're right it takes 6 months a
where you think nothing has really
changed. You can't really find the
meaning and one day they wake up and the
the with a flip switch and it's just an
interesting experience to look at. But
both scenarios could fit in this
integration session. It just would
change depending on well how are we
actually getting this um these solutions
that were presented by the medicine um
into someone's daily life into their
personality the solutions that that they
didn't know existed
how do we allow that to bridge and I
don't think it'll be a single session
usually um but I do think that there are
multiple points of integration where you
stop and say, "Okay, we're working with
the professional. We're we're still
processing those experiences and we're
looking at how has my, you know, if it
was for treatment resistant depression,
PHQ9 changed over time, how has um
our our quantitative, you know, analysis
changed?" So it
there are many parts that an integrator
or a practitioner would have to play.
But I think that given the fact that
they could say, you know, it's supposed
to be an ongoing care type of thing that
they may be able to
help in
integrating as a whole. But you're
right, it will never be done in that
that check-in right after. That's not
integration. That's a check-in to say,
"Hey, we're just making sure that like
after you left nothing bad started to
happen, like you're not
perpetually nauseous or um
you know, other lasting side effects.
>> Well, yeah, you're talking about
tracking tracking harm reduction like
like Yeah. So, harm reduction reporting
is super important. We need to make sure
that we have the touch points to be able
to report back on those things. We don't
actually have touch points for harm
reduction reporting for that's patient
centric for anything after that single
session which is severely irresponsible
like there should be touch points like
like based on the therapeutic design
much further out. So, if you have a a
I'm trying to get all the words right.
Provider
licensed private licensed provider. You
heard it here first. Um
they should based on the treatment plan
have an idea of when they need to like
when that person is going to need to
touch a check-in, you know. So,
integration session. Yeah, that is a
definition of a thing. We still need to
define integration how the program sees
it. We can't have an integration session
if we don't have a definition for
integration. This is my request. I will
provide input as needed in writing.
All right. How would you feel about like
um incorporation of
new mental processes into daily living?
I mean I would ask
Kate Hawkha
Washington
Leonard
and Mets Larry Leman to sit down
and see what they think together.
Those are subject matter experts.
Yeah, I agree. Um, and they will
definitely be referenced. That's why
we're not going to adopt anything before
we've given it a chance to send out
because I'm sure once they see the
document that they will have thoughts or
questions, comments, concerns, or
additions that we can definitely make.
But I don't think for general principles
just to review,
we
can't move forward without a pretty
standard definition of what integration
means in other areas of
healthcare. Um, Don,
>> I' just like to say I I agree with you,
Ian. I think uh the definition would be
the in incorporation of the psychedelic
experience within everyday life. I think
incorporation might be a a good word to
include in in integration.
Cool.
All right. I've gone ahead and updated
it to where integration is the
incorporation of psychedelic experiences
into a patient's daily life, ongoing
treatment, and long-term health goals.
um
that is based on the Miriam Webster
definition of integration. Um
just and from what I've seen with
psychiatric practice in general, but
again I will definitely reach out to
Khawk, Larry Leman. Um once I look back
at the transcript and remember the other
names that you had mentioned um I will
also work on reaching out to them just
to get their ideas and pick their
brains. I was really hoping um there
would be more people just to I like to
bounce ideas off and get um all the
input I can but we will make do with
what we have and continue forward. So
with that being a temporary definition,
how do we feel about the other general
principles, the integration planning,
the individualized care, the patient-
centered approach? Should we have any
other
effects?
All right. And then this uh deviates
from
psychiatric care generally in a lot of
ways. Um and that's coordination of care
and their modalities. I definitely don't
know the correct answer, hence why it's
in bold and says um committee
discussion. Horge, if you could scroll
down just a little bit.
Cool. Um,
so different options for integration
that I've seen are solo versus group. um
the different modalities I've seen in
the research and if there are any I'm
missing we definitely
uh feel free to bring them up but
acceptance and commitment therapy
mindfulness based cognitive therapy um
sematic experiencing and internal family
systems as long as well as quantitative
progress tracking um but outside of that
I don't really have a lot of information
so again I would have to defer to those
other experts see what they say um and
get kind of more information. But when a
patient has an established therapist,
counselor, psychiatrist, or other
behavioral health provider, um the
medical psilocybin provider is
encouraged with the patients written
consent to coordinate care and
facilitate continuity of treatment. We
don't want to, you know, break up any
pre-existing behavioral health um
relationships if not necessary. Um but
of course we will leave that to the
patient to um go with the integration
timeline was actually based on what Kate
had brought up in the last meeting. Uh
so she talks about um initial
integration. That's your just assessing
their physical recovery, their
psychological stability, their sleep,
appetite, mood, general functioning.
It's generally a day to 72 hours after
administration. And I'm not thinking
like a complicated assessment, but a
text to say, "Hey, are you doing okay?"
Um, or however they prefer to be
contacted. Um, and also identifying any
significant emotions, insights or
concerns they may be feeling. Um, we
don't want to overly burden them and try
to have a whole um, session directly
after, but we do just see, hey, are
there any things you notice? Are there
is there anything you are starting to
see that are very bold and blaring?
[snorts] And then the ongoing
integration um typically in studies from
1 to four weeks post administration um
translating those insights into
achievable behavioral goals, identifying
changes that support the patients
treatment objectives, um processing
unresolved emotions or difficult
experiences, and developing coping
strategies and grounding techniques. Um,
we'll also be strengthening healthy
relationships and community supports and
determining whether additional
behavioral health services or referrals
are clinically appropriate. So, the
number and frequency of integration
session should be determined by clinical
judgment and individual patient needs.
So, they could begin planning um how
many integration sessions they're going
to need before um you know they have the
administration, but of course it's going
to be different for every um patient.
And so I don't want to make a hard
minimum and say, "Hey, you have to go to
extra therapy even when you've already
actualized." And I don't want to say,
"Hey, you only need to go to one if you
need more than that for your, you know,
reaction to the medicine."
[clears throat]
for documentation.
Um they'll report date, duration,
setting of any integration
records, patient reported summary of the
dosing experience and key emerging
themes. Um assessment of mental status,
safety, mood, sleep, and functional
status. Um objective measures, any
reported adverse events or clinical
concerns and updating to the overarching
treatment plan and care coordination
efforts.
All right. Um, again, not finalized, not
needing to be finalized. This is still
has to be widely distributed. So, um,
and also check against, you know, what
the broader community thinks. So
questions, comments, concerns at this
time
or any committee discussion that you
guys would like to
have.
Gregory Evans,
>> I would propose that we change the name
of the the 24 to 72hour session to be
something that is more aligned with
[gasps]
um
[clears throat] what was the wording?
like a required provider check-in or
uh something like so like the reason to
ha the need to have that immediate touch
is
apparent right so we need to have that
uh session to capture the client
experience to
um
get immediate information about any
anything that came up, right? So, like
while it's fresh. So, like the sooner
the better. I think having the 72 hours
is like edge case like you know allow
for you know planned or unplanned things
but I think calling that
integration it there's [clears throat]
so many
there's such a Hanifa is trying to get
in the system or get in the meeting
she's having trouble guys
Um
yeah, if we call that session
integration, those who don't actually
work in the space will just be like,
"Oh, I integrated.
We're done here." Um whereas like true
clinical practice is going to prepare
people
uh for like the process, right? and that
check-in
super super important like not saying
it's not um but I think that if we find
language to
extrapolate out the the length and
independent and
uh different types of ways that we
integrate then then we'll and we put
those words into the program we'll have
uh less
uh I don't know my words are
I apologize for the I agree I don't
think we should like in terms of the law
um we have to have at least a
preparation administration and
integration session I don't think like
that text being like
how are you feeling you okay should
count as integration you're right I
don't want someone to walk out and just
be like, "Well, I checked in. I
integrated. I'm never talking to that
person again." Um because that wouldn't
be beneficial to the patient, to the
system. So, I agree. I put it as initial
check-in instead. Um
still going to put it under the
integration timeline cuz it's
technically after administration and
there's no really other place that it
would go. Otherwise it would just get
cut from both administration and it
would get cut from integration.
But um I agree. So it'll be an initial
check-in instead of initial um
integration.
Gregory.
Um, I just wanted to plant a seed.
Um there's [clears throat] a bunch of
uh research
uh crosswalk that should happen covering
not only this but the preparation like
all of the all of the stuff that we're
like framing out in this work group
[clears throat]
the I think by like September 11th we
should have like the full map of schema
that the researching continues
improvement
committee is going to be recommending
for um what's collected by who and when
and how like what technology systems and
blahy blah. Um [clears throat] but
although I know this is not like
uh like like that level detail of a
document, I think we should kind of like
sit down between now and then at some
point and just see what all those point
data points look like, how they fit into
the mapping of this. And it could, you
know, some of that could affect
uh
like the broader planning for like the
scope of data collection,
right? And two, once we finish these
three, I think they could go through and
say which where are we collecting what
cuz at that point you would have
basically a flow of prep to admin to
integration and each are going to have
to enter their own, you know, bit of
information, right? admin is going to
have dosage prep is going to have
pre-existing conditions. Integration is
going to have um you know experiences
and that kind of thing. So
or whatever ends up being I don't want
to speak and oversimplify anything but
um yeah I think that would be a good
idea. Um, I'm not going to lie. Data
collection technologies,
no idea. Not I don't that is not my
specialty at all. I am I am not good at
information technology despite um my
young appearance and [laughter] yeah.
[gasps]
Yeah. Anyway, [laughter]
Gregory.
>> Yeah, it's not so much the technology
part of it. It's just like the
importance of understanding like who's
going to how who like people get real
concerned about like how they're
reporting things. So it's like
[clears throat]
from the perspective of this group what
types of things that the structure of
this
recommendation
needs to collect and then making sure
that we're touching all of those points.
However the touching happens, however
the data collection happens, it's not so
not as much the point. But like for
example, it's like
do we want to ask people to
um
have independent
integration
metrics over extended periods of time?
Or are we just going to collect one data
metric?
because we would be using quantitative
data metrics. I think it only makes
sense to do it over time. Um it would
also help to show us things which we
have evidence on but it it it's not the
best like durability. um there's a range
where it could be and so that may help
us to establish a better understanding
of durability which will help us to um
you know if it's found that you know
it's durable for
a year then maybe we match
cannabis licenses uh cannabis medical
cannabis cards and say we'll have the
doctor issue it once
2 years and then you can still get you
both of your treatments um if the
durability turned out to be a year and
without having to get another renewal
and then every let's say 2 years you
could go in um and get it but the whole
period you should probably be reporting
that quantitative data. I think that is
one of the
horror
facilities of the medical cannabis
program was we never checked in and said
did this medicine work for you? Um
we just go off of do they renew and now
that doesn't really help us either
because you can just pay the tax instead
of renewing. So it's a very interesting
problem. altogether. It is very early in
the morning. It is a very interesting
problem altogether. Um I don't even know
where I was going with that anymore. I
just
think that yes, uh collecting the data
over a longer period of time would be
more beneficial.
Greg,
>> I just wanted to check in on how like
the cannabis is helping. [laughter]
>> Oh, so I'm joking. I'm that was I'm
being silly. Yeah, cannabis has me in a
fog. Um [clears throat] I don't I don't
really But um can we go back to u that
definition that you wrote down earlier
and just kind of review that for a
second? If we can put five on it.
Uh integration is the incorporation of
psychedelic experiences into a patient's
daily life, ongoing treatment, and
long-term health goals.
>> Can we include meaning making?
>> Sure.
patience life.
We have longterm in there.
I would change ongoing to long-term. Uh
maybe ongoing. I don't know. That's
debatable.
Integration is the incorporation of
psychedelic experiences into a patient's
daily life, long-term health goals, and
meaning making.
Anyone else in the room?
Nothing from Don. All righty. [snorts]
Oh, there we go. Thumbs up. See?
All right. So, is everyone okay with
distributing this to the rest of the
committee? Um, and allowing us to
continue discussing at a future time,
as well as of course reaching out to
Kate, um, Larry, seeing what their
thoughts are. Um, and then reporting
back to the committee
and the other experts. I just really
need to review the transcript.
>> I can send that to you now if you want.
>> Yeah. Can you just put it in chat?
>> That's too much for chat. Shoot me your
email and I'll send it to you.
>> Okay.
Um,
can you send it to the medical
psilocybin one and then they'll forward
it
for record keeping
maybe? Let's see.
I mean, they Yeah, they have their own
transcript, but [clears throat]
they don't publish it for about six
weeks.
>> Is it?
>> Um, I think Heneifeha just had her hand
up.
>> Oh, Henifa, did you have something? I'm
sorry, my people did not show it.
>> Hi. Yes, good morning. Um, I'm just
jumping on here. I was on another call
earlier. I'm trying to wrap my mind just
I just saw the definition. So, I is
there something about like it's a it's
an intentional process is something that
I would work in there. I think
everything else is great, but just
um
yeah, but I I can um I just need to look
at it again as I am trying to give input
and I'm just kind of wrapping my mind
around this, but
let's see. Okay, I'm seeing you type.
That looks great. Cool.
Awesome. That that was all you guys are
doing great.
>> Perfect. Thank you. No, we I welcome any
additions, comments, concerns. Um we
were just actually discussing whether to
because we did not have time to send
this out to the committee. We um were
wondering if we were if it was ready to
just kind of go out to the broader
committee, see um what we can, you know,
kind of review before just sending out.
That way it's not just my draft. It is
at least some other people saw it. Um
but Gregory, I saw your hand up for a
second. Intentional
>> there's you have intention process
intentional. I'm sorry.
>> Oh, you are correct.
>> Okay.
Um, do you want to talk about do you
want to include any of the domains of
care language in here?
Um, see
I mean
>> so Ian you have you have like the you
have you have kind of you've covered
like the individualized care you
mentioned group down below. Can you
scroll down to the second page?
Okay. So yeah.
So in here is there anything you want
>> how how far?
>> That's good. Right. Uh, I would go up
like six lines
like into that other page right there.
So that coordination of care, you can
put the top at the coordination of care
headline just so we can read that. Um,
does that make sense what I'm asking?
Yeah. to keep like the safe, effective,
patient centered, timely, efficient,
equitable.
>> No, no. I want if the screen could take
the coordination of care header two and
move that to the top of the screen so
that we can read the whole section
together.
>> Scroll down a little bit
>> more other way.
>> Other down
>> until
a little bit more.
[laughter]
my 5-year-old like when she wants me to
move something on the TV and she wants
it to go down, she says up. And I
realized that she like she's trying to
she likes to use she learned um h how to
use a Mac, how to scroll on a Mac, like
where you roll the ball. [laughter]
>> And so for down she says up.
>> Um [clears throat] okay, so there's
there's headers.
>> Who's who's driving?
>> I'm sorry. [laughter] Hold on. Ian and
where do you want me to go? So scroll up
until at the very top of your screen it
should just say coordination of care.
>> Got it. Got it. Okay.
>> You want me to reduce the screen is so
that more is on the page.
Does that work or
>> that work?
>> Yes. Thank you. Um
>> yep. [clears throat]
>> What is the intention of this section
for you Ian? What do you want to get out
of this? What what is what are we doing
here?
>> Looking at what modalities are, you
know, best, which are ones that are
acceptable. Um, should we allow solo
versus group? Should we like that's why
it just says committee discussion
because I honestly don't have a good
answer. Um, so should we do solo versus
group? Should we um what modality should
we allow? What um you know things do we
need to coordinate between sessions?
What kind of thing there? Um Gregory.
Um so
uh
I think taking here let me pull my
thoughts together while Heneifea takes a
minute.
>> Cool.
and then you get to speak.
>> Thank you. I I'm wondering about is is
this um
a place where the the state should be
making recommendations and regulations.
I'm just curious about the intent of
this document altogether because when it
comes to integration, it's so dependent
on right the client and the individual.
So, in terms of dictating what the c the
domains of care should be
>> and what that that care plan is, I I
just don't I'm not sure
>> I'm not sure what the the state's role
in deciding what that should be.
>> None of this would be regulation. It's
just general guidance. So, it's are we
looking at are we looking at what this
should be? It's not going to be like a
hard, you know, you can't do this. is
just going to be are we going to say
that this is, you know, the best we can
do? Are we going to say this is the gold
standard or are we going to um you know
take a step back and
just say you know what we don't have
guidance on coordination of care cuz we
could just as easily strike the entire
section and the integration guidance
still holds being that we want you know
um
if I could scroll on my screen I could
tell you um [laughter]
that we want like integration planning
to happen before they're dosed that we
want, you know, the care should be
individualized. You shouldn't try to
push your beliefs onto them. Um, that
kind of thing. And the still the
integration timeline, so the initial
check-in between before 3 days and then
ongoing in integration, which can last a
long time. Um,
>> but that could all stand without us
saying, you know, which of these
modalities, that's why I just brought it
up for discussion for what did people
think cuz I have no need for a
coordination of care guidance. um that I
could we could just as easily just say
um it's up to that's the point of
picking your you know healing center is
what modalities they are going to use
and just not give guidance.
>> Thank you for the clarification and
again I apologize for hopping in midway
through the meeting. I didn't realize
this was like a guidance document and so
that makes me
>> Yeah. No, you're good.
>> Feel better. Yeah, I I felt like giving
Yeah, I think you can you can take a
step back. I think dialing these is
starting to get into like the details of
how the care will be coordinated and I
just don't know if people will need
that, you know, sort of recommendation.
I don't that's just where where I sit as
somebody who does a lot of integration.
Um so thank you for that one.
>> Yeah. Um, actually, Gregory, would you
be cool with just cutting the
coordination of care and giving that
discretion more broadly to healing
centers?
>> Um, can we uh check in with Jorge? He's
had his hand up for a minute.
>> Oh, sorry, Jorge.
>> Yeah, my arm was asleep. Thanks, Greg.
Just kidding. Um, so yeah, I I you Ian,
you answered that you answered Heneifh's
question. Hagenifa. Uh yeah. So that was
exactly right, Ian. What you're saying
is that what what what this is going to
be is definitely a best practices guide
for folks and you know practitioners,
facilitators, clinicians to take a look
at uh these recommendations go to the
advisory board which once they are
approved or changes are made then yeah
then the the department of health will
will create users user guides for for
those folks. Yeah. So, these are not
going into the rules.
Thanks, Sam.
>> Thank you, uh, Gregory. I think I saw
Yeah.
So yeah, I think zooming out
[clears throat]
like Hanifeha was pointing to to
describe
that during you know just to cover like
during the preparations we create a
treatment plan and a integration plan
those things are definitely
individualized. Um, I think
like
touching on what needs to be reported is
maybe something that lives more in the
rules, but like when if you're talking
about a guidance document for people,
like they need to know what type of
information that they need to be
reporting back. um and which is not
specifically designed to cover the
process of care. Um
I'll think of some language. I think
it's worth having the section right. Um,
I don't know
if if maybe the title could change from
coordination of care to um
like
care planning or integrative care
planning or something that that that
points to developing a plan that's not
just about therapeutic sessions, right?
So like where integration is like all of
the stuff in your life, the little
things, the way you make your coffee,
who you call when you're sad, like that
sort of stuff. Um [clears throat]
it might land better from the
perspective of informing
those types of things that Jorge was
suggesting that this would later inform.
I think there is value in throwing in
somewhere if it's not here just like the
breadth of types of things that people
can like access and consider integration
beyond
the
beyond the licensed provider checkin.
Um but we might also in down below in
the integration timeline
um utilize that space to
from a department perspective. That's
where this group can kind [snorts] of
influence
uh the language around
what types of
therapeutic sessions are involved over
the course of time? Like, does this
person have regular talk therapy? And
does that regular talk therapist have
the ability to
zip information over to the licensed
provider to
pro to kind of start shaping qualitative
progress
um outside of instrument tracking. Um
but yeah, apologies if I'm drifting too
far from scope.
No worries. So we can definitely
I will work on
something like that in terms of what
they need to report. Um, I get very
anxious about reporting qualitative data
to any um, like data collection system
cuz that gets very close to reporting
health records. Um, which I know like
quantitative data is, but it's a lot
harder to piece quantitative data into
who someone is than it is to take their
words and try to I don't know. I might
be completely off on that aspect. Again,
researching that data collection is not
my specialty. Um but I do think there is
value in you know advising where we
should have those entry points. Um so
maybe at some point um after we adopt
the integration
you know guidelines then we can
have a meeting with RCI together to look
at what points along these plans would
you like to collect this information?
What information is valable valuable to
you when um and try to go on that front.
Um, I'm very much a patient advocate and
a privacy advocate, but I do also
believe in the power of um, real world
data. So, I am very torn on the issue.
Um,
but I don't know if that answered your
question. Um we will work on language to
get more data collection after we get
the integration care guidelines because
then we can before we send it to the
board we can have a collaboratory
meeting where we
look and say hey um which are
going to be
important where is it important and when
is it important to collect that um
information because that is going to
change What our data, how valuable our
data is to research,
Gregory.
Um, I don't see I heard you say the word
allow
um earlier. I think it's not on the
page. I just want to make sure we're not
like
saying allow
um just the kind of mindset of
>> like allow like
>> type types of integration experiences
types of like do we allow group or solo
like it really shouldn't be about allow
or disallow it's like
>> no these all I say is approaches may
include
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I think maybe it was
just a word you said earlier that
>> Yeah, I might have
>> not on the Yeah, they're early. It's
very early. [laughter]
>> All righty. Um,
so with that, I will go ahead and work
on reddrafting those. I will get them
distributed to the community or to the
committee um
before Friday unless Oh, Hanifeha, did
you have something to add?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I just dropped in the
chat a link to the circle of care uh
program that we're running with um the
UNM study and there's a section that
says seven domains of care and the
circle of care is about ongoing
integration support. Um so those I'm
just recommending you look at those
seven domains and then click on each of
them that and it gives you even more
detail about what's under that domain.
That might be useful as you're reshaping
this section.
Yes, because
the domains I care are the medical
domains of care from like hospitals.
[laughter]
>> Um, so I was looking at the complete or
thinking of the complete wrong list. I
have seen this list before, but I have
Thank you for that resource. I
definitely be considering it more
closely.
>> Awesome. Thanks.
>> Perfect. All righty. So, I will go ahead
and work on getting this re um touched
up. I will have it distributed hopefully
before Friday. Um do you guys want to
meet in say 2 weeks
um to review the new updated version?
It's still no adoption but to try to get
those contacts out um to the specialists
as well.
Questions, comments, concerns?
Gregory,
>> literally can you just say that again? I
totally missed what you said.
>> Yeah. So, um [clears throat] does would
everyone be good with um meeting up
again in two weeks? I can get the
updated version of this document
submitted hopefully before Friday. Um
and then we can rem as a committee, give
everyone a little bit more time to um
make it and then um
go from there as well as reaching out to
the experts in their field. Just getting
comments, questions, concerns, seeing
what edits they would make. Um and then
we can bring it back and
review it again.
>> Two weeks would be good for me. Um
wondering if you have if you could send
like the breadth of what this group is
covering so we can see what's remaining
after this and maybe go back and
>> recycle what what has been written so
far.
>> Okay. Yeah. cuz I think as we're getting
into like September, October, we're
going to be approaching like our kind of
like
end of days
in [snorts] terms of like cycling
through uh rules making.
>> Yes. Um
>> and not that this is rules, but like the
language the language needs to crosswalk
and and co-inform.
>> Yeah. Um, so definitely we can start
working on what other aspects of our
committee role. I'll go ahead and um
send those out um as well when the first
email goes out. I'll just incorporate
them into or I'll send them out as two.
But um yeah, I can get that to you.
If my calendar would work with me, that
would be great. My computer's no excuse
to be tired. [laughter]
Ian, you were looking at at you were
suggesting two weeks from now that would
be the n Wednesday the 19th
>> at 9.
>> Uh, you know, is one available?
>> Let me see.
Uh, it does look available. Johnny, do
you have do you see anything else that
looks available on my end? Um 19th the
19th at one looks free to me.
>> Yep.
>> Perfect. All righty. I will see you all
in two weeks.
>> Bye guys. Thank you.
>> Thank you everyone.
And
we're done recording, Johnny.
>> Wow, that is hard with three people.
Yeah. Yeah. [gasps]
Yeah.